<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/sabbatical/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/sabbatical/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-05-12T18:35:27+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sabbatical/</id><title type="html">A windy sabbatical!</title><subtitle>Blog by an expat settling into New Zealand, becomming a dad, urban farmer and having his first sabbatical.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Prelude</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sabbatical/sabbatical/update/2017/05/11/prelude.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prelude" /><published>2017-05-11T22:26:35+12:00</published><updated>2017-05-11T22:26:35+12:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sabbatical/sabbatical/update/2017/05/11/prelude</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sabbatical/sabbatical/update/2017/05/11/prelude.html">&lt;p&gt;Have wrapped up work in Sydney, and took a single flight Sydney -&amp;gt; Wellington on April 28th!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next year will be my &lt;em&gt;first sabbatical&lt;/em&gt; and needless to say I’m excited! My biggest fear is wasting my time and realising the year
is over and feel like I did not use the time wisely. How many people are blessed enough to have a year off? Not many as far as I know..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a few months wrapping up work, talking to friends and making a list of things I want to accomplish. I was 
ready to start kicking butt on my list of amazing things to do.
However, while reading
through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0825305640/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0825305640&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=0tt0-20&amp;amp;linkId=be40a38ecd5ef44c6807db5c47d79826&quot;&gt;Reboot Your Life&lt;/a&gt;
, actually &lt;em&gt;taking&lt;/em&gt; that last flight, and talking to my partner I decided chilling out is important too.
 I decided to take the first 3 weeks, while on leave, and still employed by Atlassian, as a not-quite-standard-but-still-a holiday, and use it to
 sort out mundane but important basics like getting an IRD number, arranging health insurance, rest up from a year plus
 of the weekly roundtrips between Sydney and Wellington -scaling 2 hours of timezone difference, at times 10 degrees of
 of temperature and looong days after crazy early morning flights. In between doing that I can also get a head start on
 setting up some of the projects that are part of that year list but take a little preparation and or time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I’ve done in the last 2 weeks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got an IRD number, simple like in Australia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up health insurance, surprisingly difficult compared to Australia. I’ll write about that elsewhere and update
the link here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/otto25/recommend&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; board to manage my projects in the house, and my sabbatical. I’ve got
three boards up: one for house projects, shared with my partner, one dedicated to my sabbatical, and one to study work done
as part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/open-source-society/computer-science&quot;&gt;Open Source Society University&lt;/a&gt;, which is a clone of
the &lt;a href=&quot;https://trello.com/b/9DPXYv5f&quot;&gt;OSSU Trello board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Painted the new bedroom we are building inside of the current living room. Sounds claustrophobic? Our room is 3 meters high and still
has enough room to comfortably fit a normal dining table, book case and lounge area with sizable couch. Could not get away
in my old 65 m2 apartment in Amsterdam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got things set up to start growing 2 vegetable patches, next steps: fetching the soil, and start growing!
This is blocked on finishing up the chicken coop and run.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ordered 4 chickens, cleared out space in the garden behind my shed and office space, and got started on my first “real”
DIY project: building a chicken coop. Next: building the fence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I would have done differently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;None so far!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous: &lt;a href=&quot;/sabbatical/bio.md&quot;&gt;Bio&lt;/a&gt; Next: &lt;a href=&quot;/sabbatical/02_list.md&quot;&gt;The list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TODO:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;think up / off / write up reason, and angle. Why? Accountablility? How to live a different life?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write up / link up health insurance story/stories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write up / link to the chicken coop story/stories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write up / link up to veggie garden story/stories&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;write up / link to year list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Have wrapped up work in Sydney, and took a single flight Sydney -&amp;gt; Wellington on April 28th!</summary></entry></feed>